MARKETING & STRATEGY

An innovative, multi-disciplinary marketeer with a track record of ideating, planning and executing campaigns and content using data and insight to inform creative and strategic narratives across multiple mediums.

I enjoy developing and executing marketing plans, putting them into action, exploring and researching trends and reports, supporting clients and teams, creating content, analysing customer behaviours and delivering strategic results that have a positive impact. I bring digital marketing expertise, creativity, organisation and a passion for, and extensive knowledge of online / offline marketing.

I have experience within a number of industries: tech (SAAS), digital publishing, e-commerce, luxury fashion and beauty retail, independent music artists, FMCG, micro SMEs and agencies.

With 7 years' experience and mentorship from industry veterans, I have finely tuned a range of skill sets that demonstrate my entrepreneurial spirit to take on projects with initiative, confidence and attention to detail.

EMPLOYMENT

Freelance

Marketing Specialist October 2021 – Present

Creative Strategist & Producer (Nov 21 - May 22)

Nami – Independent music artist
 Produced a creative campaign and developled content plans, on-line identity for a new song release to help build a loyal fan base across Instagram and strategic actions for Spotify.

Creative Producer and Marketing (Jan 22 - Mar 22)

Esta – Independent music artist

Produced a music video, liaising with third-party contractors, scouting talent and locations, filmed and edited BTS footage for Instagram content. Developed an Instagram campaign strategy for song a release to increase listeners on streaming platforms.

Social Media Manager (Sept 21 – Dec 21)

Papillon Kia, Pre-loved Luxury Retail
 Implemented social scheduling tools for Instagram, Tik Tok,
 Facebook, Twitter and creating posts, stories, videos, captions, hashtags and supporting the online rebranding.

Consultant - Marketing and Business Strategist (Jul 21 - Sept 21)

Sans Bourn, Luxury home accessories website
 Developed a 1-year business and marketing plan for the launch
 of an e-commerce website on SquareSpace.

Digital Marketing Specialist (Jul 20 - Jan 21)

Beautiology Ltd, Cosmetic Luxury e-Commerce website
 Created an online website and developed online branding – this
 included web design, copy writing, branding (logo, tone of voice,
 mission) product shoots, online admin, audience research, device
 testing and more.

Creative Marketing and Content Creation (On-going)

ACE Esthi Chique, SMPU Artist
 Content creation for online posts and videos (Instagram) and offline marketing collateral (flyers, banners, brochures), developed
brand guidelines for Instagram and designed an exhibition stand.

Digital Marketing (Mar 20 - Jan 21)

Gazelle, Website Solution for SME's
 Launched a marketing website with publishing house (DC Thomson) and Better than Paper. This included website design, copy writing, logo creation, audience research and tone of voice for specific industry verticals.

SKILLS

- Content Marketing / Creation
- Campain Strategy / Planning
- Copy Writing and Graphic Design
- Research, Insights and Data
- Project Management / Events
- Building Relationships / Partnerships and Networking
- Offline and Online Marketing
- Social Media Planning
- Brand and Identity Strategy
- Photography / Filming / Editing
- Natural Creative and Tech Savvy
- Team Work and Leadership
- Photoshop / InDesign / Premier Pro / Final Cut Pro / After Effects
- HubSpot Marketing Pro
- Google Analytics / Tag Manager / Cloud Console / SEO / PPC
- Facebook / LinkedIn / YouTube / Google / Instagram / Ads
- Comfortable with Mac, PC and easily able to pick to up new soft ware and hardware.

HOBBIES & GOALS

I enjoy travelling, photography, DJing, swimming and finding fun activities

I love sewing in my free time, finding new recipes to try out, reading magazines and books and bingeing on a great TV series.

My goal is to expand my portfolio of work, fine-tune my skillsets, and ultimately manage teams and execute larger, global projects.

EDUCATION

University of Roehampton | 2013 - 2016 Bachelor's degree in Journalism and Media Communication - 2.1

City and Islington College | 2011 - 2013 A Level: Media Studies (A), English Literature (B) and Philosophy (B)

CONTACT & REFERENCE

+44 79299 79381 anjana.v@hotmail.co.uk West London

References sent upon request

EMPLOYMENT

Clientshare: SAAS Workflow Tool Marketing Executive | Full-time

Mar 2021 - Dec 2021

- Working closely with Head of Marketing. Executing marketing plans for upcoming launches, supporting various departments and ensuring the re-branding is communicated across the business.
- Supported the launch of a new product and business re-brand I created a social media strategy and content, managed a website launch, organised a launch event, liaised with internal departments and agencies to ensure all collateral is on brand and message.
- Planned and executed the 'Pulse' Launch event (Sept 2021) for blue-chip clients, investors and partners (this included stage rehearsals, invitations and emails, location, playlist, food and drinks, directed the team on event day and ensured the evening ran smoothly).
- Built an automated email workflow for free-trial users, increasing sales and engagement.
- Developed and executed a social media strategy and content on business accounts (LinkedIn and Twitter) that helped build a sense of community within the supplier sector.
- Co-ordinated, tested and launched a new website with a creative marketing agency and ensured HubSpot CMS is easy to use for everyone in the business.
- Supporting departments and third-party contractors: Sales, Design, Client Success, Enterprise Account, IT and Agencies with collateral developments / amends and product announcements.
- Supporting and developing outbound, inbound and ABM marketing campaigns.
- Filmed and directed a six-part video series of senior team members to share the 'Clientshare' story within target community.
- Organised the internal files for the business in SharePoint and communicated to the team.
- Presented weekly marketing meetings to senior leaders (Marketing, Finance, Sales and MD).

Better than Paper: Digital Publishing tool for brands and publishers

Digital Marketing Executive

Sept 2016 — Jul 2020 | Full-time / Jul 2020 — Present | Freelance

- Reporting directly to the CEO and Marketing Director, I assisted with the creation of business and marketing plans, investment decks, pitches and presentations.
- Executed a marketing strategy that increased ROI across multiple industry verticals.
- Managing CRM for the business and executing personalised email campaigns across vertical sectors; finance, media, tech, automotive, luxury, publishers, FMCG and SME's.
- Copy writing for websites, social, email, PR, case studies, SEO, articles and sales collateral that generate leads, increase brand awareness, engage customers and build traffic to website.
- Creating digital content and executing ad campaigns across social media via: LinkedIn and Facebook ads
 with clear plans and goals.
- Capturing monthly reports on web traffic, email campaigns and social media to ensure KPI's are met as well as optimising plans for improvements and sharing this with the rest of the team.
- Liaising with clients, designers and IT teams throughout the process of internal and external projects (websites, apps and digital magazine launches) to ensure a smooth operation.
- Building partnerships with industry trade bodies: FIPP & PPA.
- Managing and implementing a national telesales campaign.
- Attending meetings and working directly with CMO's and directors for blue-chip brands such as AXA, DC Thomson, OSN Media and L'Oreal on large scale projects in a consultative way.
- Identifying new trends in digital marketing, evaluating new technologies and ensuring the business and client projects are at the forefront of industry developments.
- Creating website and brand proposition for sister company; Gazelle.